# **Becca King**

# TITLE

Full-Stack Web Developer with Journalism Experience

## CONTACT

216-570-0627 rebecca.lynne.king@gmail.com Cleveland, OH 44102

#### **WEBSITE**

rebeccaking.info

#### **SKILLS**

JavaScript
JavaScript libraries (jQuery,
Parsley, React)
CSS
CSS preprocessors (Less)
HTML5
Progress OpenEdge
Microsoft SQL Server
Google Tag Manager and
Google Analytics
Git version control

#### **EDUCATION**

General Assembly
Software Engineering
Certificate program in
full-stack web development.
Created web applications using

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

I am a full-stack web developer with a background in journalism, and I am passionate about creating engaging online experiences for diverse audiences. I've worked closely with news editors, information technologists, designers, and e-commerce experts.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Amerimark Direct, LLC, Web Developer

Middleburg Heights, OH - Nov 2020 - Current

- Primary front-end specialist on a team of web developers.
- Developed front and back end solutions based on design specifications and information technology needs.
- Completed training in React, SQL, and web accessibility.
- Contributed to the redesign of five sites to make each responsive and reduce reliance upon third parties.

#### Self-employed, Freelance Writer

Jan 2020 - Current

- Wrote magazine articles for *Teen Vogue* and *LGBTQ Nation*.
- Researched and reported original news stories for *The Athens News* and *The Athens Messenger*.
- Worked as a ghostwriter for We Write Blog Posts, later promoted to an editing position.

#### North Coast Media, Web Developer

Cleveland, OH - Jan 2020 - Jul 2020

- Full stack development of websites based on a WordPress CMS.
- Technologies used include HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, WordPress, PHP, SQL, Google Tag Manager.
- Developed websites to work properly across multiple browsers, including those created by Microsoft, Google, and Mozilla.

JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, Angular, React, SQL, MongoDb, HTML, CSS, Git version control.

Miami University
Bachelor of Science
Kinesiology
Environmental Science
University Honors Program

E.W. Scripps School of
Journalism, Ohio University
Master of Science
Journalism
Athens, Ohio
Completed two years of
coursework in digital media,
communication law, and media
economics before leaving out
of medical necessity.

# Ohio University, Graduate Assistant in Journalism

Athens, OH - Aug 2017 - May 2019

- Studied the fundamentals of online journalism, communication law, and media economics to become a well-rounded professional in the journalism field.
- Worked as a research assistant in journalism for varied university departments.
- Received mentorship from top professionals in the journalism industry.

# Americorps - La Puente Shelter, Community Educator and Volunteer Coordinator

Alamosa, CO - Aug 2016 - Jan 2017

- Created news and radio press releases on behalf of a rural homeless shelter.
- Built relationships with the local community and visiting volunteers.
- Gathered and edited stories for and designed a 32-page storybook on behalf of the organization. Used Indesign and Adobe Photoshop under the guidance of a professional graphic designer.